（ライブ）ボンでの国連気候変動会議での公開講演
(Live) Public Speech at UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn
今日のセッションへようこそ (司会者 ドクター・シュー)
Welcome to today's session (Moderator Dr. Xu)
中国のエネルギー転換と技術革新についてですが
So on the topic of Chinese energy transition and technology innovation,
私たちは現在、気候変動に対する取り組みの緊急性と
we find ourselves like in the middle of an era where both the
技術革新の必要性の両方が緊急である時代にいます
urgency of combating climate change and the need for technology advancements.
中国はこの課題の最前線に立っています
So China stands in the forefront of this challenge due to huge
そして莫大なエネルギー消費
population and also huge energy consumption.
今から10年後に進んでみると、中国は
Fast forward 10 years to today, so China has emerged as a
世界のリーダーとして太陽光発電を導入し
global leader in solar power deployment and it claimed the largest market
そしてバッテリー駆動の電気自動車市場でもトップ
and for the battery-powered electric vehicles.
脱炭素産業のアップグレードを推進するため、中国は水素を
So committed to a decarbonized industrial upgrades, China has recognized hydrogen as
有害な化学物質の代替エネルギー源として認識しました
an essential energy resource rather than hazardous chemicals.
これは2020年の中国の国家エネルギー法案草案に記載された重要なシフトです
So this has been a significant shift that already noted in its
また、14か年計画にも発表されました
national energy law draft of 2020.
また、中国はクリーン水素技術への巨額の投資を行っています
So as announced also in the latest 14th five-year development plan,
持続可能な水素経済を促進するための重要なステップを踏んでおり
China has taken extraordinary steps with substantial investment in clean hydrogen tech
また、カーボンニュートラルの達成に向けた取り組みの一環として
to foster a sustainable hydrogen economy and also further to achieve its
2016年までのカーボンニュートラル目標に向けています
commitment to carbon neutrality by 2016.
大陸を越えて、ヨーロッパは新しい章を開いています
So across the continents, another chapter unfolds.
ヨーロッパは持続可能性へのコミットメントと気候変動への大規模な取り組みで知られています
Europe is renowned for its long-term commitment in sustainability and tremendous
気候変動との戦いで
actions in climate change.
また、ヨーロッパはクリーンエネルギー技術を喜んで受け入れてきました
And also Europe indeed has embraced clean energy technologies wholeheartedly since last
世紀
century.
ヨーロッパのクリーン水素アライアンスやレパワーEU計画のような
Ambitious initiatives like European Clean Hydrogen Alliance and also the Repower EU
これらはイノベーションを促進し、世界的な協力を育んでいます
plan are fueling innovation and fostering global collaboration.
2022年に発表された欧州水素銀行は、最初の
The European Hydrogen Bank announced by the European Union in 2022 with
30億ユーロの初期資金を提供しています
an initial funding of 3 billion euros.
この銀行は、ヨーロッパの水素市場を新たな
The bank aims to boost the European hydrogen market to a
レベルに引き上げることを目指しています
brand new level.
ドイツ、オランダ、フランスなどの国々は引き続き大規模な投資を行い
Nations like Germany, Netherlands and France, they are also making significant investment
水素インフラに投資し、クリーンエネルギーの導入を推進しています
in hydrogen infrastructure, pushing the boundaries of clean energy adoption.
デジタル持続可能性は、デジタル化と持続可能性の融合です
Digital sustainability, the marriage of digitization and sustainability.
それは私たちの持続可能な未来に向けた道のりにとって非常に大きな約束を持っています
So it holds immense promise for our journey towards a sustainable future.
デジタル持続可能性の力は、成長している新しい星のようです
The power of digital sustainability, such as a rising new star, everyone
ChatGBT、ブロックチェーン、人工知能、IoTが
knows, chatGBT, blockchain, artificial intelligence and the Internet of Things
私たちがエネルギーを生産し、分配し、消費する方法を革命的に変えています
is revolutionizing how we produce, distribute and consume energy.
これらの技術は、エネルギーシステムを最適化し、効率を改善し
These technologies enable us to optimize energy systems, improve efficiency and
再生可能エネルギー資源の統合を強化します
enhance the integration of renewable energy resources.
エネルギーシステムが賢く、相互接続され、反応する世界を想像してみてください
Let's imagine a world where the energy systems are smart, interconnected and responsive.
建物や都市は、電力、熱、さらには水素を生成して分け合うエネルギー拠点になります
Buildings and cities become like energy hubs, generating and sharing electricity, heat
そして水素
and even hydrogen.
再生可能エネルギー源は、電力網にシームレスに統合されます
So renewable energy sources are seamlessly integrated into the grid, creating a
分散型で弾力性のあるエネルギーネットワーク
decentralized and resilient energy network.
クリーンエネルギー技術である水素を採用し、デジタル持続可能性の力を活用することによって
By embracing clean energy technologies such as hydrogen and leveraging the power
私たちはこの転換を前進させるために必要なツールをすでに手に入れています
of digital sustainability, we process the tools already and to drive this transition forward.
政府、産業界のリーダー、研究者たちは、世界的な舞台で協力し
So governments, industrial leaders and researchers, we must collaborate on a global
革新ソリューションを開発し、クリーンエネルギーとデジタル持続可能性で動かされる
stage and to develop innovation solutions and forging a path towards a
持続可能な世界への道を切り開いていかなければなりません
world powered by clean energy and driven by digital sustainability.
(終了)
(End)